This...
is Resembool?
It's awfully...
I'm sorry it's too rural for you.
He's still looking.
What's the matter?
He's been looking at me
ever since we were on the train.
You can understand why, right?
It's a crime to be so beautiful.
Um...
You're Sara, aren't you?
You sure have grown up.
N-No, I'm not!
For crying out loud, pretending to be someone he knows! That's the oldest...
Sara...
That was my mom's name...
What's this? You said you were going to study in Rush Valley,
but you've been in Central this whole time?
It's not like that. We've been keeping an eye on Ed and Al.
You don't say.
So, when are those two coming back?
Oh, yeah, Grandma, I met someone in Rush Valley who said they knew you.
Grandma, no one's home!
No one, okay?
Good grief...
Just a moment, please.
Wow, the power of love!
You've come back, have you?
Pinako-san, I can't seem to locate my house.
Your house, as such, is no longer...
Grandma, you know this man?
Ah, right. You were still
so little, and all.
This man is Ed and Al's father.
Yeah, and coming back
after being away for so long,
I can't seem to find my house.
The Philosopher's Stone.
Those who obtain it are set free from the Law of Equivalent Exchange.
There is no need to pay a price
in order to obtain something, either.
We sought it and found it.
How come you're so fast?
Huh? My body just seems
awfully light for some reason.
If you're tired,
should we take a break?
We can't.
What you said before
was probably the truth.
About Führer Bradley?
That man... the Führer...
is a homunculus!
This time, the Führer was
commanding the mission.
I don't think it was Envy
taking his place.
Besides, the Führer's secretary was a homunculus.
If we go back to the military, you and I both would be...
Then, Brother, sure enough, that secretary lady is—
Don't say it!
But Sensei said that homunculi are made when a human transmutation fails.
I told you not to say it!
Al...
What was that just now?
A huge gate...
I've seen it before, too.
Brother, was that truth?
Sensei said it was
something else, but yeah.
How did that happen,
when all we did is touch?
As an alchemist, I must have unknowingly made the Philosopher's Stone react.
Brother, do you believe it, then?
That I've become
a Philosopher's Stone?
I don't feel like that's
what happened myself.
After all, the Philosopher's Stone
wouldn't be...
Nobody has ever seen one.
Whatever form it takes, it wouldn't surprise me.
But never mind that.
Don't get too close to me.
Brother...
If we inadvertently touch again, it will spark another reaction with the Philosopher's Stone.
There's no sense in having you disappear before we can take your body back.
Brother, where are we going?
Resembool.
That's where the military will look first.
Those homunculi are
sure to come after you.
If we're going to beat them,
there's something
that we have to get.
Kimbly was apparently confirmed dead
in front of that red light.
However, at that moment, Scar was still alive.
It appears that the townspeople fled outside the city before the military rushed in.
We've discovered an underground passage, and we're tracing where it leads now.
Does this mean they
weren't trying to resist?
Was their objective
to use the military as ingredients,
making the whole city a transmutation circle?
Ed and Al appear to be safe.
Several soldiers witnessed Ed outside the city.
They said that about an hour ago, Ed and Al were leaving the area.
Could they be continuing
on their journey? Even so...
I doubt that they were helping Scar to create a Philosopher's Stone.
Colonel!
28 dead, 67 seriously injured, including five officers.
There are still over 900 others missing.
We will conduct a thorough
investigation as to what happened.
There is one person who
knows exactly what happened.
Scar, you mean?
The Fullmetal...
The Elric brothers.
For what reason
did they show up in Liore?
We believe that
they were pursuing Scar.
Why? Did he have orders
to subdue Scar?
No, they were engaged in various
fields of inquiry and alchemic research.
They appeared in Liore
and had dealings with Scar.
Have as many as a thousand officers
and men become casualties as a result?
It's not as though he has a rope
around the Elric brothers' necks.
I would like to give them
a chance to explain themselves.
Are you saying you will
apprehend them yourself? Very well.
But if you fail to catch them, you will be the one who will have to explain himself.
Go with them.
According to my intelligence,
the Elric brothers might be fighting alongside a seditious element that calls themselves homunculi.
Catch him and bring him back.
If it gets out of hand,
I grant you permission to pass judgment on him on the spot.
Colonel...
You heard what he said.
Sort through all the information we have
on sightings of the Elric brothers.
Are we really going to
go after Ed and Al?
Those are our orders.
But this was the work of Scar.
It's also partially Archer's fault
for being reckless.
I don't know what went down here,
but the brothers—
The fact is, they've run away.
If we let them go, it's going to come down on the Colonel.
He said that if things get out of hand,
the Colonel was to kill them!
Shall we get going, Colonel?
Yeah.
Did you stay here again
all last night?
Huh?
I just don't have a good grasp on my sense of the passage of time.
How many years has it been
since Trisha died?
It's been six years now.
I see. The children
must have grieved, huh?
Sara Rockbell?
But I thought you were Sara.
I told you before, remember?
I'm Winry.
Sara was my mother.
So that's how.
The war, huh?
It wasn't just war.
They were killed.
And by a soldier who would ordinarily be their ally.
All because they treated
friends and foes impartially.
That's so sad.
Please don't make it
sound so simple.
It's not just sad.
I...
know the man who
killed my parents.
I also know that he is
by no means a bad person.
So I can't even do
anything about it.
That's why...
That's why it's so sad.
Winry-san! I'm so hungry!
L-Lieutenant Ross!
And Brosh!
You really have come after us, haven't you?!
It's because we saw something we weren't supposed to see!
Oh, sure enough,
you've come after us!
Scieszka!
I never knew.
Those boys don't even have a home anymore.
How do you mean, those two are being pursued by the military?
We got an emergency phone call,
from the east.
They said that by the Führer's order, we were to apprehend the Fullmetal Alchemist and his brother,
and that they'd been in contact with the masterminds behind the revolt in Liore.
What are those guys doing?
Someone I'm close to in
Communications told me.
Currently, a search party is being
drawn up by Major General Hakuro.
Word has probably already gone out to local police.
Once that happened, the Lieutenant suddenly took some leave.
And here I thought
this would be a date.
It's nice to be able to
breathe the clean air, isn't it?
How can you go to all this trouble
just to tell all this to a wanted man?
What are you talking about?!
Even if the Führer did order it,
I don't believe it!
How could those two be rebels?
Uh, I didn't mean...
Still, we don't know whether or not
the two of them are even coming here.
No, they'll come home.
Even without a house to return to,
this is still their home, right?
Besides, you're here, too.
Long ago, there weren't
any railroads into here.
There wasn't even a single road that went further east, either.
Everyone used to climb the mountain alongside that stream
until it finally let out in the east.
We used to play a lot
by that stream, long ago.
That's it! If I were Ed and Al,
I would definitely come that way.
Thanks, Uncle!
Un...cle?
Let's go, Scieszka!
Ross-san, you guys stay here!
If the search party shows up,
we'll slow them down as best we can!
Thank you!
There weren't any
railroads into here?
But that was over
a hundred years ago...
Al, hide!
Brother?
Just take cover!
So ultimately, this is all
just about some promotion?
I wouldn't say that's the only reason.
He said so, didn't he?
If the Elric brothers get away,
the Colonel will bear full responsibility for what happened in Liore.
The Colonel will?
In that case, there isn't much we can do, huh?
H-Hey there, Edward-kun.
Just as the Colonel predicted.
You're taking the side road to your hometown that you're used to taking.
Well, let's go.
Move.
Ed-kun?
I'm never going back to the military!
Go ahead and fire!
See whether or not you can
shoot through my Automail!
E-Edward-kun, why?
Go ahead and shoot!
Stop!
Havoc-san...
We aren't going back.
Al, let's go!
We're sorry!
Come quietly!
Edward-kun!
If you've got something to say,
we're all ears!
We aren't your enemy!
You can prove your innocence as much as you want to during the formal inquiry!
You'll be okay for now.
Do those two seriously
mean to turn against us?
We'll find out
when we catch them.
Nobody get cold feet next time!
Colonel, um, could you
get into my breast pocket?
Take better care of yourself.
They couldn't have gotten very far.
Probably because they can't very well
expose Alphonse to the water.
Because of his bloodseal.
Out of the way!
Who was it that told you about the Elric brothers?
Nobody.
Do you seriously think that those two are rebels?
We'll know once we catch them
and interrogate them.
You're the one who recruited Ed and Al, aren't you?!
And now this?!
It's no use.
The only thing this man is interested in
is his rank within the military.
Answer me!
Was this how it was when you killed my father and mother, too?!
Brother?
Don't touch me carelessly!
We don't know what will happen!
Why are you running?!
Ed! Al!
Winry!
Because you're chasing us, that's why.
When a dog is chased, he runs away.
A well-trained dog never
goes against his master's orders.
Did you say "master"?!
Or, have you suddenly
gone back to being a stray dog?
Relax, Edward-kun.
Even if you were cursed as a dog of the military,
you would put up with it
in order to achieve your goal.
Isn't that what you said?
I'm through being
a dog of the military.
Does this mean you're going back to being
a helpless child who won't listen to reason?
Call it whatever you want!
You're slipping, Colonel!
Al!
Major!
Sir!
Al!
I transmuted the stone projectile in mid-air...
...and I compressed the air within it and ignited it.
An effective attack, was it not?
That must have come in handy
in Ishbal, huh?
Brother...
Stop!
Please... stop...
Winry...
Once, I killed two people.
They were doctors.
There were no friends or foes
among their patients.
That's what they said as they treated those around the battlefield.
However, those whom they treated became our enemies.
The military repeatedly asked them
to stop treating our enemies,
but they refused to listen.
I was given an order...
and I... shot them.
Ever since, I swore that
even if I were under orders,
I would not follow anything that was unreasonable.
That I would put myself in a position where I didn't have to follow them.
The reason I'm chasing after you is not because I was ordered to.
It's because I'm pissed off at you!
Why did you run off on your own
without coming to me for protection?!
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 44: "Hohenheim of Light"
What the hell are you doing here...
you rotten old man?!